Hello everyone, today in this video
I will introduce two
keywords to help us throw
errors called "throw with 's'" and "throw
without 's'".
I've noted them down here. One
is plural and the other is singular. I'll
give an example. Here, I'm
opening it like this. You
can directly click on the
scanner. Press and hold the
Control key and left-click. That will open
the class, the scanner part. Inside,
press Ctrl and
F, then search for "
throw". Click on the
file. Here
you will see that inside,
click
here. Inside, you will see that
sometimes we use the flow
to throw errors, but
note that when we look
like this, we see that it
throws outside the function.
This "Pro" keyword is written inside.  Outside of
the function, if you
look at the keyword row without the letter S,
you'll see this. Let's search
to see where it's used. Here, in the
next file, you'll see that the throw doesn't have the
letter S. You can see that
with this keyword, the throw doesn't have the letter S; it's
usually written inside the function. So,
what's the point of having or not having the letter S?
Here's a
bonus link for you.
You can go to the
stack flow and look at it.
Usually, we can write
code like this, or you
can write code like this. We throw it
directly outside the function. So
why do we throw
this exception outside the function?
Usually, you should note
that in a large project, the
terminal will show you
where our error started and
where it ended.  When logging
system activity, we want to record
the code's journey, from
which file to which line, and
which line causes the error.
Using this `thow` statement will log the error
directly within that method. This is
very convenient, so
typically, if you write a
general function that's used in many places,
you should
use this `thow` statement.
If
we write a general function or class that
can be reused,
we call it throwing an
exception, not something inside the `
try and call` method. Please note
this. When
using the `throw` statement,
you can write it there if it's convenient; it's
not necessary to
write it inside the `thow` method.
For example, sometimes you
want to throw an error directly, and you're hesitant to
write the `try and call` statement, right?
You can write an `ifl` statement like this:
So, you can throw errors directly, and please note
that when we throw errors,
we only throw one error at a time.
If
you use the `throw` function,
you can throw as many errors as
you want. For example,
look here; it throws two errors
at once. This means it
writes a general function and
throws as many errors as
you want. That's the meaning of it.
These two keywords only serve one
purpose: you throw errors whenever you want,
and it's not
dependent on our `try and cash` method.
In the next video, I
will guide you. We will
do some small exercises together to
practice the knowledge we have
learned.